<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>About</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">About</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                     (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
             <div type="text">
                 
                 <p>This edition of the Inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica (2020) is being published to mark the 102nd birthday, on 18 December 2020, of Joyce Reynolds, 
                     of Newnham College Cambridge, the principal author. It would be misleading to describe this collection as complete. 
                     We are presenting everything available to us, including texts published up to 2012. There will be other texts not yet published; 
                     there will be further illustrations and other data for the texts presented here. We would welcome further material for an eventual further edtion; 
                     we hope taat readers wiill feel free to download, republish and enhance these materials
                 But our principal intention is to enable others to benefit from Reynolds' work, and to stimulate and enable further study and understanding of Roman Cyrenaica.</p>
                 <p>
                     In 1948 Joyce Reynolds was based at the British School at Rome, from where she started a series of regular visits to Libya, 
                     to study the inscriptions of the Roman period. She worked initially in Tripolitania: her epigraphic corpus, 
                     the <hi rend="italic">Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania</hi>, 
                     written with John Ward-Perkins, was published in 1952, and an enhanced edition was published online in 2009. 
                      
                     In 1951 she first visited Cyrenaica, and since then has collected and studied the inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica, working with local archaeologists 
                     and others from Italy, France, the U.K. and the U.S.A.. She continued to visit Libya almost every year until 2008, 
                     and assembled materials for a corpus of over 2000 inscriptions from Roman Cyrenaica. Nearly a third of these have never previously been published, 
                     while others have only appeared in versions which can be very much improved, and better understood, as a result of re-reading. 
                     The majority are accompanied by photographs collected by Joyce Reynolds and her colleagues 
                     (in particular Elizabeth Rosenbaum-Alföldi and Hafed Walda), or given to her by the Libyan Department of Antiquities. </p>
                 <p>The transcriptions of the texts were made and organised by Joyce Reynolds; in 2007 they were entrusted by her for publication to Gabriel Bodard, and 
                     Charlotte Roueché and Hafed Walda. Bodard then oversaw the transfer of the texts online, in EpiDoc markup; this served as a training for many students (see below). 
                     Further texts were added from publications by Reynolds. All the materials have been stored an cuated by King' Digital Laboratory.</p>
                 
                 <p>In 2008 an IRCyr team - Joyce Reynolds, Hafed Walda, Charlotte Tupman and Dorothy Thorn - visited Libya; they recorded valuable new data 
                     and Walda made an important collection of photographs.  Reynolds had provided  some 3000 photographs, taken by her or her 
                     colleages (particularly Elizabeth Rosenbaum-Alföldi) given to her by excavators, or by the Libyan Department of Antiquities. These were 
                     digitsed, again under the supervision of Gabriel Bodard.While some were clearly associated with the relevant texts, others were not. 
                     Once the texts were in digital form, and searchable, it became possible to identify many more photographs. Pietro Liuzzo did the fundamental work,
                     followed by Roueché.<!-- more herec --> </p>
                 
                 <p>A challenge which had been of concern to Reynolds for many years was the difficulty of providing accurate geodata for a country wher such information was 
                     restricted on security grounds. The emergence in the 2000s of publically available tools based on satellite imagery, such as Google Earth,
                      transformed tfor this, among many archaeological projects. To test the possibilities, the IRCyr team collaborated  with Valerie Scott, 
                      of the <ref target="https://www.bsr.ac.uk">British School at Rome</ref>,  Dr Tom Elliott, of
                      <ref target="https://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades</ref>,and with the <ref target="https://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/home"> Epigraphische Datenbank Heidelberg</ref>, in the  
                     <ref target="https://concordia.atlantides.org/">Concordia</ref> project; they undertook to digitise Reynolds' earlier publication of the Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania. The BSR had already put the 
                      texts into digital form, and had digitised the important collection of accompanying images. The team transformed the text into EpiDoc; 
                      they made no editorial changes to the content, but Reynolds provided neout.xmlw English translations for all the texts. 
                      Walda provided co-ordinates for all the locations, which could then be mapped onto Google Earth.</p>
                 
                 <p>The resultant resource was published in 2009, <ref target="http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/irt2009/">Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania (2009)</ref>, and received with enthusiasm, particularly in Libya, where it was presented in Tripoli in May 2010. 
                 Later that year the IRCyr team was approached by the group responsible for French archaeology in Libya, then led by Professor André Laronde; 
                 their epigrapher, Professor Catherine Dobias-Lalou, was preparing the publication of the Greek inscriptions of Cyrenaica from the pre-Roman period, 
                 and of the verse inscriptions. Dobias-Lalou and Reynolds had collaborated for many years. It was agreed that Dobias-Lalou, with the support of a team at Bologna, 
                 would publish her collection onlin, in EpiDoc, using the same stanards as those being used for IRCyr. The resultant corpus was published in 2017: 
                 <title>Inscriptions of Greek Cyrenaica</title> and <title>Greek Verse Inscriptions of Cyrenaica</title> at 
                     <ref target="https://igcyr.unibo.it/">https://igcyr.unibo.it/</ref>.
                 </p>
                 <p>Dr Walda had built a database for the geodata for the Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitana; he went on to add equivalent data for the Cyrenaican 
                     texts. It became increasingly clear that this was producing a resource which was useful in its own right, and could record other significant locations, 
                     providing Unique Identifiers and multiple toponyms. Roueché, aided by Dr Valeria Vitale, added information from Geonames, Pleiades, and from specialist sources, 
                     such as the Archeological Guides by Philp Kenrick. Neil Jakeman, of 
                     King's Digital Laboratory, created an interface which allowed the publication, in 2016, of the 
                     <ref target="https://www.slsgazetteer.org/"> Heritage Gazetteer of Libya</ref>; data continue to be added by volunteers.</p>
                 
                 <p>Each of these initiatives allowed Roueché to further refine the analysis of the original collection of texts: filling lacunae, identifying duplicates, 
                     and enriching the bibliography. In this she was greatly helped by Catherine Dobias-Lalou, with her profound knowledge of the sites.</p>
                 
                 <p>EFES</p>
                 
             </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
