<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>About</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">About</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                        (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <p>The aim of this publication is to maintain and develop a tradition of international collaboration - between archaeologists and epigraphers from many countries, and their 
                    colleagues in Libya - in publishing the inscriptions of Libya. The inscribed texts presented here have been published by a range of expert scholars. They have been assembled  and 
                    curated by Charlotte Roueché,
                    and their publication in this format has been enabled by her colleagues, Gabriel Bodard (London) and Irene Vagionakis (Bologna). The aim is to make to provide a richly documented 
                    corpus of these materials in a format which is easily accessible, easily searched, and freely available. </p>
                <p>In 1946 the archaeologist John Ward-Perkins, who had served with the British Army in Libya during the second World War, was appointed Director of the British School at Rome (BSR), while 
                    Richard Goodchild (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/66544871">VIAF</ref>), another British archaeologist, was appointed Director of Antiquities under 
                    the British Administration of Libya. In the same year Joyce Reynolds, a classics graduate working on Roman history came to Rome on a scholarship. 
                    Over the next few years the three worked together to collect and study the Roman inscriptions of Tripolitania; based in Rome, Reynolds was able to collaborate 
                    extensively with Italian archaeologists who had studied and published many of these texts. The resultant work, 
                    <hi rend="italic">Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania</hi> (IRT), was published in 1952, and was a model of collaborative work.</p>
              
                <p>A major weakness of the 1952 publication was the limited amount of illustration that was possible, from the 
                very large collection of photographs held at the BSR.  
                The production of an online second edition of IRT, with full illustration, was first suggested to the British School by Michael Greenhalgh 
                (Australian National University), who produced a prototype version. A subsequent version was developed on the basis of his work by a BSR 
                team assembled by Andrew Wallace-Hadrill, the Director; this included Raphael Helman, Sophy Downes, Raphael Cormack, and Jo Wallace-Hadrill, 
                who together prepared the whole text in electronic form. The best form for publication was however not yet clear. In the 2000s Reynolds, 
                and her pupil Charlotte Roueché, who had been working together on the inscriptions of Aphrodisias, also started to explore online publication, 
                using <ref target="https://sourceforge.net/p/epidoc/wiki/Home/">EpiDoc markup</ref>. A challenge which had been of concern to Reynolds for many years was the difficulty of providing accurate geodata for a country 
                    where such information was restricted on security grounds. The emergence in the 2000s of publicly available tools based on satellite imagery, such as Google Earth, transformed this, 
                    among many archaeological projects. To test the possibilities, therefore, Reynolds, Roueché and Bodard agreed with the BSR to use IRT as a test case, working with
                    Dr Tom Elliott of <ref target="https://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades</ref>, and with the Epigraphische Datenbank Heidelberg, in the 
                    <ref target="https://concordia.atlantides.org/">Concordia</ref> project. The team transformed the text into EpiDoc; they made no editorial changes to the content, 
                    but Reynolds provided new English translations for all the texts.  The resultant resource was published in 2009, <ref target="http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/irt2009/">Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania (2009)</ref>, 
                    and received with enthusiasm, particularly in Libya, where it was presented in Tripoli in May 2010.</p>
                
                <p>The 2009 publication included no items beyond those published by Reynolds in 1952 or added in 1955. Since 1955 many scholars have worked on the inscriptions of Tripolitania, 
                    both improving the published texts and publishing new ones. This work has been faithfully recorded in <hi rend="italic">L'Année Épigraphique</hi>;  
                the <ref target="https://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/home"> Epigraphische Datenbank Heidelberg</ref> made the texts available in EpiDoc XML, which has simplified the process of adding the 
                new texts to the present collection. In every case we have presented the most recently published version of the text.</p>
            </div>
           
           
           
            <div type="text">
                <head>HGL</head>
                
                <p>Dr Hafed Walda undertook the mapping for the Concordia project, and provided co-ordinates for all the locations, 
                    which could then be mapped onto Google Earth. In the process he built a database; he went on to add equivalent data for the texts in the sister project, 
                    Inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica. 
                    It became increasingly clear that this was producing a resource which was useful in its own right, and could record other significant locations, 
                    providing Unique Identifiers and multiple toponyms. Roueché, aided by Valeria Vitale, added information from Geonames, Pleiades, and from 
                    specialist sources, such as the Archeological Guides by Philip Kenrick. Neil Jakeman (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4049-3789">ORCID</ref>), 
                    of King's Digital Laboratory, created an interface which allowed the publication, in 2016, of the 
                    <ref target="https://www.slsgazetteer.org/">Heritage Gazetteer of Libya</ref>, under the aegis of the <ref target="https://societyforlibyanstudies.org/">Society for Libyan Studies</ref>; data continue to be added by volunteers.</p>
            </div>
           <!--  <div type="text">
                <head>GODOT</head>
                
                <p>A characteristic aspect of inscriptions in Cyrenaica is that they very frequently contain a detailed calendar date. 
                    In 2017 we started a discussion with colleagues about how to contribute this data to a Gazetteer of dates, 
                    where information about a specific date could be collected: conversion to its Julian or Gregorian form, and an indication of documents containing that 
                    particular date. Frank Grieshaber of Heidelberg (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2733-6941">ORCID</ref>), working with us and with 
                    Mark Depauw (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-0460-3987">ORCID</ref>), put forward a proposal to the <ref target="https://mellon.org/">Mellon Foundation</ref>, 
                    which was approved in 2018. The resultant database, GODOT, is available at <ref target="https://godot.date">https://godot.date</ref>; 
                    at present it draws on the documents in IRCyr, 
                    on inscriptions in the Epigraphische Datenbank Heidelberg, and in a large collection of papyri. 
                    It is our hope that other scholars will both contribute to and benefit from this resource.</p>
            </div> -->
            
            <div type="text"> 	            	 
                <head>EFES</head>
                <p>The appearance at the end of 2017 of the open source <ref target="https://github.com/EpiDoc/EFES">EFES</ref> publication platform has 
                    opened new possibilities for the open and sustainable publication of a digital epigraphic corpus such as IRT. 
                    EFES is based on the <ref target="https://kcl-ddh.github.io/kiln/">Kiln</ref> platform 
                    developed for publication of TEI XML projects at the <ref target="https://www.kcl.ac.uk/ddh">Department of Digital Humanities</ref> and 
                    <ref target="https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/">King’s Digital Lab</ref>, which is used for several EpiDoc corpora; 
                    the game-changing features of EFES are its focus on EpiDoc XML and inclusion of epigraphic indices by default, and its adoption by the EpiDoc development community.</p>
                
                <p>The EpiDoc Front-End Services tool (EFES) was designed to fill the important need for a publication solution for researchers and editors who have produced 
                    EpiDoc-encoded texts but do not necessarily have access to digital humanities support or a well-funded IT service to produce a bespoke Web publication for them. 
                    The EFES development team, led by Bodard, comprised Polina Yordanova (customisation, testing, training and documentation) and Jamie Norrish (software development), 
                    and the tool was further tested and developed by several collaborators from other projects, including 
                    Martina Filosa (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-1900-4231">ORCID</ref>), Tamara Kalkhitashvili, 
                    Alessio Sopracasa (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7973-7301">ORCID</ref>), 
                    Simona Stoyanova and Irene Vagionakis. EFES can be deployed with a minimum of technical skill, and may also be customised with a wide variety of display, index and 
                    search features, either from the EpiDoc toolkit, or custom built for the individual project.</p>
                
                <p>EFES therefore provided the basis for the <ref target="https://ircyr2020.inslib.kcl.ac.uk/en/">IRCyr2021</ref> digital publication, which means that it is 
                    compatible and consistent with other EpiDoc publications, 
                    and especially future instalments of the Inscriptions of Libya corpus. The use of standard indices, search facets, and authority lists of terms 
                    such as monument types, symbols and lists of people and places will enhance cross-corpus interoperability, and enable integration with large multinational projects 
                    such as the <ref target="https://www.eagle-network.eu/">EAGLE Network</ref> and <ref target="http://epigraphy.info/">Epigraphy.info</ref>. 
                    Planned future developments in EFES, including built-in geographic visualisation, date and time search, and Linked Open Data export functionality, 
                    will easily be adopted into the platform, and offer new features to Inscriptions of Libya projects. It is our intention to develop 
                increasing interoperability and cross-searchability between all the projects.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>IRT2021</head>
                <p>In 2018 a grant from the Society for Libyan Studies enabled Simona Stoyanova to set up an EFES edition of the Inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica. 
                    A further grant from the Society, in 2021, has allowed us to start work on preparing IRT 2021, an enhanced and enriched version of IRT 2009, 
                    in a more stable digital structure. The corpus will be made accessible initially to a limited group of colleagues with direct experience of 
                    working with the inscriptions of Tripolitania; they will be invited to contribute in any way they 
                might wish, whether with emendations, illustrations, or even new items. We very much hope that this can provide an example of a new level of collaborative work in epigraphy, 
                using the digital environment to build on the principles of the original publication.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>CCH/KDL</head>
                <p>The project began in 2008 at the Centre for Computing in the Humanities at King’s College London, then headed by Harold Short; 
                    in 2015 it migrated to <ref target=" https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/">King's 
                    Digital Lab</ref> where it is currently under Service Level Agreement: see 
                    <ref target="https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/our-work/archiving-sustainability">https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/our-work/archiving-sustainability</ref>/ for this provision.
                    Throughout the history of the project it has been generously supported by a range of colleagues; 
                    in particular Miguel Vieira and Jamie Norrish are the architects and developers of Kiln, 
                    which forms the basis for EFES; Neil Jakeman created the Heritage Gazetteer; Ginestra Ferraro advised on the design; Tim Watts has helped curate the images; 
                    Brian Maher provided regular technical guidance. </p>
               <!--  <p>
                    This therefore is the account not just of a publication, but of a project, only made possible by the generous provision of skills and guidance 
                    from a wide range of experts. For further details of contributors see <ref target="./team.html">Team</ref>.
                </p> -->
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
