<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The editorial teams</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">Team</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                        (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <head>IRT 1952</head>
                <p>John Ward-Perkins <ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/36979215">VIAF</ref> and Joyce Reynolds (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/25924">VIAF</ref>), based in the British School at Rome, 
                    with the help of Richard Goodchild (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/66544871">VIAF</ref>) worked in Libya, 
                    collecting and recording antiquities, particularly inscrptions, between 1947 and 1952. Ward-Perkins provided a large collection of photographs; 
                    Reynolds prepared the inscribed texts for publication. In this they were helped by and included contributions from several Italian archaeologists, particularly 
                    Salvatore Aurigemma (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/79347125">VIAF</ref>), Renato Bartoccini (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/76397638">VIAF</ref>), 
                    Giacomo Caputo (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/34471602">VIAF</ref>), and Pietro Romanelli(<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/9929812">VIAF</ref>). 
                    The resultant volume was published in 1952, presenting numbers 1-973, 
                and 30 plates of photographs: the remainder of the photographs were available for consultation at the British School.</p>
                
               
             </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>IRT 2009</head>
                <p>In the early 2000s Michael Greenhalgh 
                (Australian National University, <ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/54277684">VIAF</ref>) agreed with the Director of the British School at Rome, Andrew Wallace-Hadrill (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0979-9205">ORCID</ref>) that it would be desirable 
                to create an online publication of IRT, allowing for full illustration. At that time such publications were not yet common: 
                Greenhalgh produced a prototype version, and a team at the BSR including Raphael Helman, Sophy Downes, Raphael Cormack, and Jo Wallace-Hadrill, 
                 worked to develop this. In 2008 they entered into partnership with a team at King's College London - Gabriel Bodard (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8566-6666">ORCID</ref>) 
                 Charlotte Roueché (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3606-2049">ORCID</ref>) and 
                Hafed Walda) and at the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World at NYU -Tom Elliott (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4114-6677">ORCID</ref>), 
                    to produce an online publication of the 1952 volume in <ref target="https://sourceforge.net/p/epidoc/wiki/Home/">EpiDoc</ref>: some 20 further texts, 
                published by Joyce Reynolds in 1955 were added, and Reynolds provided English translations of every text; Valerie Scott, the Librarian of the BSR, 
                provided the images; Hafed Walda researched and provided the geodata. 
                IRT2009 was published online in 2009: <ref target="https://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/irt2009/">https://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/irt2009/</ref></p>
             </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>IRT 2021</head>
                <p>In 2020 Charlotte Roueché received a grant from the Society of Libyan Studies to prepare an updated version of IRT, using the EFES editing platfrom which 
                    had been used for the Inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica (2020): <ref target="https://ircyr2020.inslib.kcl.ac.uk/en/">https://ircyr2020.inslib.kcl.ac.uk</ref>.
                    Roueché continued and standardised the editing, adding further texts and references, bibliography and translations. </p>
                <p>Irene Vagionakis (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1918-7333">ORCID</ref>) established and developed the basic 
                    architecture and design of the site; she organised the conversion of further texts from the <ref target="https://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/home">
                        Epigraphische Datenbank Heidelberg</ref> </p>
                <p>Gabriel Bodard worked with Roueché and Vagionakis
                    on the editing and standardisation of texts, and and use of EpiDoc standards; he also worked on the conversion of the Bu-Njem ostraca from 
                    <ref target="https://papyri.info/">papri.info</ref>.</p>
                <p>Caroline Barron (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4878-5620">ORCID</ref>) added the Punic to all the multi-lingual texts, 
                    edited and translated a group of texts from Sirte. Barron, Bodard and Roueché worked on translating the ostraca from Bu-Njem</p>
                <p>Alessandra Giovenco (BSR) curated the enrichment of the BSR photographic collection, and the interoperability of the resources.</p>
                <p>In summer 2020 the first version of the publication was mounted online, and shared with interested scholars. As a result we received generous and important 
                    contributions, from Francesca Bigi (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/206880013">VIAF</ref>: drawings), Catherine Dobias-Lalou (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/29572722">VIAF</ref>: advice on Greek verse texts), 
                    Philip Kenrick (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/27195649">VIAF</ref>: photographs), Robert Kerr (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/27392821">VIAF</ref>: advice on Neo-Punic and 
                Latino-Punic texts), Michael Mackensen (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/29549642">VIAF</ref>: comments and photographs), 
                    Ignazio Tantillo (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0870-9626">ORCID</ref>: comments and photograph). 
                We have been able to draw on previous editions and translations by these and many other scholars.</p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="text"><head>Technical development</head>
                <p>IRT 2009 and IRT 2021 are hosted at King's Digital Lab, King's College London.</p>
                <p>Arianna Ciula, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4247-1073">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Deputy Director and Senior Research Software Analyst, 
                    supported requirements elicitation as part of KDL effort on archiving and sustainability of legacy projects.</p>
                <p>Ginestra Ferraro <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8573-1432">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software UI/UX Designer, contributed to the design of IRT, IRCyr and HGL.</p>
                <p>Neil Jakeman, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4049-3789">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software Analyst, 
                    refined the development and front-end of the Heritage Gazetter of Libya 
                    still hosted at KDL.</p>
                
                <p>Brian Maher, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6602-6834">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Senior Research Software Engineer and Systems Administrator, 
                    is responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRT is currently hosted.</p> 
                <p>Pam Mellen (KDL), Research Software Project Manager is responsible for managing KDL archiving and sustainability effort.</p>
                <p>Jamie Norrish (CCH/DDH), independent Developer, worked on the editing framework, EFES.</p>
                <p>Miguel Vieira (KDL), Principal Research Software Engineer, worked on the architecture and development of Kiln on which EFES is based.</p>
                
                <p>Tim Watts (KDL), Senior Research Software Systems Manager, is responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRT is currently hosted.</p> 
            </div>
            
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
