<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The team</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">Tram</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                        (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <head>Editorial team</head>
                <p>Joyce Reynolds (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/25924">VIAF</ref>,  
                    <ref target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joyce_Reynolds_(classicist)">Wikipedia</ref>, 
                    <ref target="https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/fellows/joyce-reynolds-FBA/">British Academy</ref>) 
                    collected and prepared numbers 1-996, with the support of many colleagues in Libya and elsewhere.</p>
                
                <p>Caroline Barron (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4878-5620">ORCID</ref>) added the Punic to all the multi-lingual texts </p>
                
                <p>MORE CONTRIBUTORS TO ADD</p>
                
                <p>Charlotte Roueché (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3606-2049">ORCID</ref>) continued and standardised the editing, 
                    adding further texts and references, bibliography and translations. 
                </p>
                <p>Alessandra Giovenco (BSR) curated the enrichment of the BSR photographic collection, and the interoperability of the resources.</p>
                <p>Hafed Walda provided the geodata, which formed the basis from 
                    which Neil Jakeman created the Heritage Gazetteer of Libya. 
                    </p>
             </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>Delivery</head>
                <p>Irene Vagionakis, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1918-7333">ORCID</ref> established and developped the basic architecture and design of the site </p>
                <p>Gabriel Bodard (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8566-6666">ORCID</ref>) worked with Roueché and Vagionakis
                    on the editing and standardisation of texts, and also oversaw the digitisation and the construction of the publication, 
                    and use of EpiDoc standards. .</p>
              
                   
            </div>
            <div type="text"><head>Technical development</head>
                <p>The project is based at King's Digital Lab, King's College London.</p>
                <p>Arianna Ciula, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4247-1073">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Deputy Director and Senior Research Software Analyst, 
                    supported requirements elicitation as part of KDL effort on archiving and sustainability of legacy projects.</p>
                <p>Ginestra Ferraro <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8573-1432">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software UI/UX Designer, contributed to the design of IRT, IRCyr and HGL.</p>
                <p>Neil Jakeman, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4049-3789">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software Analyst, refined the development and front-end of HGL, 
                    still hosted at KDL.</p>
                
                <p>Brian Maher, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6602-6834">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Senior Research Software Engineer and Systems Administrator, 
                    responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRT is currently hosted.</p> 
                <p>Pam Mellen (KDL), Research Software Project Manager responsible for managing KDL archiving and sustainability effort.</p>
                <p>Jamie Norrish (CCH/DDH), independent Developer, worked on EFES.</p>
                <p>Miguel Vieira (KDL), Principal Research Software Engineer, worked on the architecture and development of Kiln on which EFES is based.</p>
                
                <p>Tim Watts (KDL), Senior Research Software Systems Manager, is responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRT is currently hosted.</p> 
            </div>
            
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
